So we have a tumbling asteroid hazard
我们有会翻转的小行星
and we can destroy it with our laser bolts.
我们可以用镭射子弹消灭它
But the entire process seems a bit dull.
但这个过程似乎有点无聊
So let's add some explosions to brighten things up.
让我们加点爆炸的效果进来
Let's open our DestroyByContact script.
打开DestroyByContact脚本
The first thing we need to do is add a reference
首先我们要做的是增加对
to our explosion visual effect.
爆炸效果的引用
So let's write public GameObject explosion
所以敲下代码public GameObject explosion
then after our boundary detection code
然后在边界检测代码后面
write instantiate.
键入instantiate
We know instantiate, we've used it in
我们在之前的Player Controller脚本里面
our Player Controller script.
用过instantiate
Let's open our Player Controller script.
让我们打开Player Controller这个脚本
And copy the instantiate line.
然后复制instantiate的那行代码
Paste it in to our DestroyByContact script.
粘贴到DestroyByContact脚本中
What do we want to instantiate?
我们要实例化什么呢?
Our explosion.
我们的爆炸
Where do we want to instantiate it?
在哪个位置实例化呢?
At our transform position with our
在我们变形组件提供的参数的位置
transform rotation applied.
将爆炸实例化
This will instantiate the explosion
也就是说在我们小行星
at the exact same position as our asteroid.
所在的位置实例化爆炸
Save this script and return to Unity.
保存这个脚本回到Unity
In the Prefabs folder is VFX Explosions.
在Prefabs文件夹中找到VFX -> Explosions
Drag the explosion_asteroid on to the
把explosion_asteroid拖拽到
Explosion slot to create a reference to it
DestroyByContact脚本中
on our DestroyByContact script.
Explosion槽的位置
Save the scene and enter Play mode.x
保存场景进入到游戏模式
Now when we destroy the asteroid we get a
现在如果消灭了小行星
very pretty explosion.
我们会看到一个漂亮的爆炸
Let's see that again.
让我们再看一次
Nice.
太帅了
On the other hand
从另一角度来说
If we ram the asteroid with our ship
如果拿玩家飞船撞击小行星
We only get that same explosion.
我们会得到一样的爆炸
Now that's a little sad.
这看起来有点弱
Let's improve this script to accommodate
我们把脚本改良一下
the player as a special case and include
让玩家爆炸成为一个特例
a player explosion as well as
并像导入小行星爆炸
the asteroid explosion.
那样导入玩家爆炸
Return to our DestroyByContact script.
回到DestroyByContact脚本
Let's add a public GameObject reference
让我们给玩家爆炸
to our playerExplosion.
增加一个引用
Then let's duplicate our instantiate code
把实例化的代码复制一下
and again, what do we want to instantiate?
重复一遍,我们需要实例化什么?
Our playerExplosion.
玩家飞船的爆炸
And where do we want to instantiate it?
在哪里实力化?
Where our player, as the other collider
在我们玩家飞船的位置
is in our scene, or the Other
当玩家飞船作为
transform position and the Other
另一个对象碰到了小行星
transform rotation.
我们飞船的位置引爆
Leaving the code like this would simply
这段代码
instantiate 2 explosions with every
如果被触发了
OnTriggerEnter event.
会实例化2个爆炸的效果
Let's test the Other collider again.
让我们再检测一下撞击对象
Indent the new instantiate code and write
把新的实例化代码缩进一下
If the other collider's tag is the
如果另一个碰撞对象的标签
same as Player
是玩家
and add an open bracket.
加上大括号
And after the instantiate line we will
在这段实例化代码后面
need to complete this with a close bracket.
我们需要大括号结束
We will now always instantiate our explosions
我们总会发生爆炸效果
but if we collide with an object tagged Player
但是如果爆炸的另一个对象的标签
we will also instantiate a player
是玩家
explosion as well.
我们将会多实例化一个玩家爆炸
Save this script and return to Unity.
保存脚本回到Unity
Our player now needs a tag.
我们的玩家现在需要一个标签
Using the Tag drop-down menu select the
打开标签的下拉菜单选择
pre-made tag Player.
已经预制的标签Player
There is no need to create a custom tag in this case.
这里不需要我们自定一个标签
Select the Asteroid game object
选定小行星对象
and drag the explosion_player on to the
把explosion_player这个爆炸效果拖拽
Player Explosion slot on the
到DestroyByContact组件的
DestroyByContact component.
Player Explosion槽
Save the scene and play.
保存场景进入到游戏模式
Wow, that's great.
哇,这回太酷了
The last improvement we need to make on the
我们最后要改进的内容是
asteroid is to get it moving towards the player
小行星最好能朝玩家飞过来
With the Asteroid selected
选定小行星
open the Scripts folder and drag the
打开Scripts文件夹
Mover script on to the Asteroid
把Mover这个脚本拖拽到
game object in the Inspector.
小行星的这个查看器窗口
The Mover script is the movement
Mover这个脚本
code we created when we were moving the bolt
是我们之前学习中做过的
game object in an earlier assignment.
让子弹向上飞的脚本
Then set the speed value to -5.
这里把脚本中speed值设定为-5
This negative speed will bring the asteroid
这个反方向的速度将使
down the screen towards our player.
小行星从上向下朝玩家飞船飞过来
Save the scene, enter Play mode and test.
保存场景进入游戏模式测试一下
And the asteroid tumbles towards our player.
小行星翻转着朝我们的玩家飞过来
Conveniently the boundary also takes care
我们的边界会
of the asteroid when it leaves the boundary's
销毁离开边界的小行星
box by destroying it.
这点很方便
Exit Play mode.
退出游戏模式
The asteroid hazard is done.
小行星制造的灾难已经做好了
We need to save this as a prefab
我们把这个保存成预制件
So drag the asteroid game object from the
把小行星这个游戏对象拖拽到
Hierarchy on to the Prefabs folder in Assets.
Assets目录下的Prefabs文件夹中
This creates a new prefab of our
我们这样就做好了一个
Asteroid game object.
小行星对象的预制件
Lastly delete the instance of
最后让我们把场景
the asteroid from our scene.
中的小行星删除
Our asteroid hazard is setup and ready to go.
我们小行星灾难已经设定好了
In the next assignment we will create
下一项任务是
our game controller.
编写我们游戏控制器